## Tri Gunawan

(+62) 85743675495 | tri.gunawan@live.com | Tangerang, Banten | https://trigunawan89.github.io/

### **About Me**

I am an information technology enthusiast with more than 7 years experience around data analytics solutions. I also like developing fullstack web and cloud solutions for the last 2 years. Currently working as an expert data analytics for Corporate Risk & Integrity at Sinarmas Asia Pulp & Paper. My main expertise is data engineering on top of SQL & Python ecosystem. My secondary programming skills are using Javascript, React/Vue and Django/Flask Framework to build an API and web applications. In my previous experience I worked mainly with commercial business intelligence tools, but now I usually use open source technology as my foundation to develop data analysis, machine learning, web applications and APIs. I love doing side projects in my free time to expand my software development capabilities in web, frontend, backend, devops, APIs, big data and machine learning.

# Experience

May 2018 - Present (2 years 3 months)

# **Expert, Data Analytics (Assistant Manager)**

Sinarmas Asia Pulp & Paper | Banten, Indonesia

#### Job Desc:

- # Design, develop and maintain data analytics, reporting systems, automation systems, dashboards and performance metrics that support key business of Corporate Risk and Integrity Management-Sinarmas Asia Pulp and Paper.
- # Manage and optimize processes for data intake, validation, data mining and data engineering as well as data visualization and communication deliverable.
- # Ensure accuracy of data and deliverables of analytical report with comprehensive policies and processes
- # Direct report to Global Head of Corporate Risk and Integrity Sinarmas Asia Pulp and Paper
- # Doing Exploratory Data Analysis & Machine Learning Modeling
- # Achievement: People Performance Organization 2020 Grade: A
- # Technology Stack: Python, JavaScript, Django, VueJS, Postgres, Anaconda, Power Bl.
- # Main Projects: Reporting & Analytics System for Corporate Risk & Integrity, Due Diligence Services Portal, Case Management System for Investigation, Security Incident Report System, Implementation Custom Sharepoint, Risk Assessment Tool, OSINT Analytics.

Oct 2015 - May 2018 (2 years 8 months)

## Senior Business Intelligence Specialist

PT. Kraft Heinz ABC Indonesia | Jakarta Raya, Indonesia

#### Job Desc

- # Responsible for new development, maintenance and evaluation business intelligence project so that the project in line with company business strategy
- # Provide recommendations and contribute as a key strategic resource for continuous improvement of existing BI System
- # Gather business requirements for new reporting, data modeling, analysis and dashboard •
- # Research and prototyping newest BI technology to line with current business trend
- # Achievement: Promotion to Senior Business Intelligence Analyst Specialist Level August 2016
- # Technology Stack: PL/SQL, Oracle, Power BI, SAP Business Object, Tableau, Access, VBA, OLAP/SSAS
- # Main Projects: Analytics Report across Finance, Sales, Distribution and Production Department, Demand & Supply Predictives Analytics

Jan 2013 - Sep 2015 (2 years 9 months)

### **Business Intelligence Consultant**

PT. Multipolar Technology TBK | Jakarta Raya, Indonesia

#### Job Desc:

# Conduct requirements analysis and design of Business Intelligence/ Data Warehouse Project # Development data warehouse, ETL, data quality, data modeling, OLAP/CUBE, reports and dashboard

# Integration testing and documentation of BI/DW Projects.

2 | Page

# Preventive maintenance, monitoring and troubleshooting BI system

# Provides training and guidance to the client in the use of BI tools

# Research newest BI/DW technology and contribute to make innovation of BI/DW solutions

# Acting as BI Solution Technical Presales

# Achievement: Employee appreciation as rookie of the year 2013, Microsoft Certified Solution Expert (MCSE) Business Intelligence 2015

# Technology Stack: TSQL, Microsoft BI (SSAS/SSIS/SSRS), IBM Cognos, Arcplan, SAS EG # Main Projects: Business Intelligence Rumah Sakit Harapan Kita, Sales Reporting Takeda Indonesia, SAS Migration Bank BNI, Maintenance IBM Cognos Bank Indonesia, Visual Analytics Multipolar Technology

May 2011 - Aug 2011 (4 months)

## **IT Support**

PT. Bank CIMB Niaga, Tbk | Jawa Tengah, Indonesia

Job Desc:

# Support to identify user's personal computer issues and advise solution

# Installing and configuring software, join domain, setting email, networks, printers and scanners

# Investigating, diagnosing and solving personal computer software and hardware faults

# Logging and keeping records of customer/employee tickets.

# Technology Stack: Network/LAN, PC/Desktop, Windows OS, MS Outlook, Printer

### **Education**

2008 - 2012 Universitas Kristen Satya Wacana

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science/Information Technology | Indonesia

Software Engineering

Major

CGPA 3.52 / 4.0

## **Skills**

SQL Server, MySQL, Postgre, Oracle, Data Science & Machine Learning, Python, Advanced

SQL, JavaScript, Big Data, Hadoop, Kafka, Spark, BI, ETL, DWH, SSIS/SSAS/SSRS,

PowerBI, Tableau, QlikView, SAP BO

Intermediate Django, Flask, NodeJS, Docker & Kubernetes, React, React Native, Vue, AWS Cloud

Solution